<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skyfarer Cloud</title>
    <description>Where I blog my (mis)adventures.</description>
    <link>https://skyfarer.cloud</link>
    <atom:link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <author>
      <name>Jeremy Walworth</name>
      <email>walworth@gmail.com</email>
      <uri></uri>
    </author>
    
      <item>
        <title>Metamorphosis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of what hopefully will be a series of brain dump posts of my
journey from practicing Christianity to practicing Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up going to a mix of Christian private schools, public schools, and
different churches. I’ve sat in all sorts of churches from mild Methodist to
weird and wild full gospel Pentecostal. My parents were Christians, and tried
very hard to raise my brother and me to be good Christian men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older I became, the more suspicious I became of what was being taught in
sermons, Bible study groups, my so called “accountability” partners. Every one
of them believed that the Bible is infallible, perfect, inspired by God Himself.
Yet, everyone had an interpretation of what it meant, and how it applied to me. 
The Bible is full of contradictions that are confusing, yet most just explain
these away with words that sound good and convincing, yet still leave the
issues unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the problems the Bible presents, the teachings of Jesus are of 
benevolence, compassion, empathy, and equanimity. All wonderful practices that
are valuable and useful to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried real hard to be the man of God I felt that I was called to be. But there 
was something that felt off about the whole charade. It wasn’t until I took
a hard look at myself that it began to make sense. Thus began my
metamorphosis from Christian to Buddhist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the posts that follow, I hope to articulate in small installments, how my
journey progressed, and how my thinking changed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 09:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//metamorphosis</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/metamorphosis"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/metamorphosis</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3D Printed Pen Holder for Journal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started &lt;a href=&quot;https://bulletjournal.com/&quot;&gt;Bullet Journaling&lt;/a&gt; last November, and
to my surprise it’s really stuck!  I’ve tried lots of different organization
systems, and none have really resonated with my brain like this has. A few
years ago, I read “&lt;a href=&quot;https://gettingthingsdone.com/&quot;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;”, and while I really
liked David Allen’s organization ideas, I just couldn’t get it to
implementation.  After reading Ryder Carroll’s “The Bullet Journal Method”,
I found myself visualizing the parts I loved about GTD implemented in my
own Bullet Journal. I can now say, after a few months, I am absolutely hooked.
I now have a journal that is always with me, and I’m feeling much less stress.
Before BuJo, I experienced anxiety and frustration over forgetting important
things. Now, when the thought enters my head, I write it in my daily journal page
and I can immediately get back to what I’m doing without losing my train of
thought.  It’s wonderful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this brings me to the subject of this post. Here’s a shot of my journal:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/penholder1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Paperage journal I found on Amazon doesn’t have a good place to hold a pen.
I can’t just use any pen either. I have to use &lt;em&gt;my favorite pen&lt;/em&gt;. Everyone has &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt;
favorite model pen, right? Mine is the Papermate InkJoy gel 0.7. All other pens
are inferior. Fight me! ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t journal without my favorite pen, so my pen needs to be with my journal,
all the time. But how to keep them together securely? I thought about designing
something in TinkerCad, but thought I’d check Thingiverse first. Well, I was
delightfully rewarded with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:1782329&quot;&gt;this simple yet brilliant design&lt;/a&gt;.
About 15 minutes later I had my pen clip printed and it works perfectly.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/penholder2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 20:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//3d-printed-pen-holder-for-journal</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/3d-printed-pen-holder-for-journal"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/3d-printed-pen-holder-for-journal</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyberdeck Part 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/cyberdeck-part-3&quot;&gt;Cyberdeck Part 3&lt;/a&gt;, I redesigned the screen brackets, and
printed up panels for the USB hub and 12V power switch/connector as well as 
brackets for the G90 control head. I also
printed up a center panel with speaker holes and a window for an OLED display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this update, I designed some brackets to hold the G90 main chassis in place.
Here’s the rendering from TinkerCAD of the G90 brackets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/g90mounts.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added a panel with two switches, an SMA connector, and a RJ45. In the
future, I’d like to add my DMR hotspot to the Cyberdeck. One of the switches
will be for turning the DMR hotspot on/off, while the SMA panel connector will
bring the DMR antenna out. The RJ45 has been wired up to a short ethernet cable
that plugs into the Raspberry Pi. For the second switch, I’d like to wire it to
a GPIO on the Pi and have it switch the Pi between hotspot mode and client WIFI
mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next panel I added has a SO-239 panel connector to bring the antenna
connection out from the G90. On the inside I’ve soldered a piece of coax with
a PL-259 on it that connects to the G90. This panel also has a port for
a cooling fan, and a switch to power the fan on/off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found an existing design on Thingiverse for a PowerPole panel mount bracket.
I’ve printed up this design and added it to the power panel. It’s wired up to
the main power switch and then to a screw terminal distribution block. Here’s where the G90
power leads are connected, and a couple of DC buck converters connect here too.
The buck converters supply 5VDC to the Pi, and the USB hub.
Here’s a shot of the assembled panel out of the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_0689.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the backside with some of the components mounted and wired up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_0691.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we are assembled in the case, powered with a battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_0694.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
 In the picture I have a 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/NooElec-NESDR-Smart-Enclosure-R820T2-Based/dp/B01HA642SW/ref=asc_df_B01HA642SW/?tag=hyprod-20&amp;amp;linkCode=df0&amp;amp;hvadid=309807187084&amp;amp;hvpos=&amp;amp;hvnetw=g&amp;amp;hvrand=14677872484702353752&amp;amp;hvpone=&amp;amp;hvptwo=&amp;amp;hvqmt=&amp;amp;hvdev=c&amp;amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;amp;hvlocint=&amp;amp;hvlocphy=1017825&amp;amp;hvtargid=pla-403313148407&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Nooelec
NESDR&lt;/a&gt;
SDR plugged into the USB hub and a P25 Trunk Tracker running on the Pi to
receive my local public safety radio system. Check out that quick and dirty
800mhz dipole stuck on the top! It’s some copper wire cut to 1/4 wavelength at
800mhz and soldered to a SMA pigtail I had laying around.  It works remarkably
well when it’s near a window of my house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next update I’ll be adding the audio interface from the Pi to the G90
for digital HF modes, and hopefully by then I can get a video posted of the
deck in operation on the HF bands!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, Happy Hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//cyberdeck-part-4</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-4"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-4</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyberdeck Part 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/cyberdeck-part-2&quot;&gt;Cyberdeck Part 2&lt;/a&gt;, I worked out a good design for the frame and positions for the Xiegu G90 head and main chassis.  In this iteration, I’ve designed and printed some brackets for the G90 control head. I also designed and printed a few of the panels. I made one that holds a USB hub, and another for the main power 
switch and the Power Pole connector for the main 12VDC supply. Next I designed and printed a center panel with speaker holes, and a place for the OLED display 
and a red push button to change the OLED display.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG-0681.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I set out to redesign the screen brackets. The previous revision had slots for screw holes because I got lazy and didn’t measure the hole placements carefully.&lt;br /&gt;
Now that I was confident on the screen position and the frame design, I was able to measure the hole placements with some accuracy. I added some additional 
holes in these brackets where I can mount stuff like circuit boards. Here’s a rendering of the screen backets I created on Tinkercad.  These are much more stable than
the previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/t725.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the G90 brackets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/g90_ears.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 11:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//cyberdeck-part-3</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-3"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-3</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyberdeck Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/cyberdeck-part-1&quot;&gt;Cyberdeck Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, I began printing off rails with hexagon holes that accept a hexagon brass nut. In this iteration, I’ve printed off more rails, 
these are a bit shorter to accomodate the curved corners of the Apache case. I also designed and printed some brackets to mount the touchscreen to the rails. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG-0671.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
I removed the control head from the G90 body and played around with locating the head and chassis. In the photo they are just sitting in the case and not mounted yet.
I discovered that there’s not much clearance between the keyboard and the panel when the case is closed up. 
So I’ve decided to locate the G90 control head all the way to the bottom so the knobs can protrude into the space above the keyboard in the case lid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that in other builds, some designers were using friction to hold the panels in place in the case. With this iteration, 
I printed cross members for the rails, which can be seen in the photo.&lt;br /&gt;
This provided some stability and helped me see how the frame can slide into the case and be held pretty well with friction alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An issue I forgot to mention in Part 1, my Creality Ender 3 printer is unable to print a piece long enough to span the entire height of the Apache case. To solve this, I’m printing two rails, each half the distance from the top to bottom of the case. I’m joining them with a bracket I’ve 3d printed and fastened them with M3 screws.  Here in Part 2, I’ve incorporated these “joiner brackets” into cross members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG-0721.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is the first iteration of screen brackets that I designed. I got lazy and made the screw holes slots so I wouldn’t have to get the hole alignment perfect. This proved to be a mistake
because these brackets keep slipping. I have to keep re-tightening the screws to keep the screen in place. I’ll be redesigning these brackets in a later iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 07:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//cyberdeck-part-2</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-2"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-2</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cyberdeck Part 1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I was poking around on the internet looking for cool Raspberry Pi
cases to 3D print. I have a few Raspberry Pi’s around that do various tasks,
and I was thinking it would be cool to print up a stylish case. Well, this is
how I stumbled on the idea of building a cyberdeck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned that the term “cyberdeck” comes from a cyberpunk book written in 1984
called Neuromancer, by William Gibson. Once I started down the internet rabbit
hole of cyberdecks, I realized I needed to build one. Checkout
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/cyberDeck/&quot;&gt;r/cyberdeck&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit to see some fun
and creative builds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a RPi that I use with my Xiegu G90 HF transceiver, for digital
communication modes like FT8 and JS8Call. I decided straight away that my
cyberdeck would incorporate the Xiegu G90, and the RPi in a single, luggable
fashion. This would be perfect for &lt;a href=&quot;https://parksontheair.com/&quot;&gt;POTA&lt;/a&gt; activations or just general ham radio
geekery while RV camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I grabbed a Pelican case knock off from Harbor Freight, calipers, and fired
up TinkerCad.  Being a pilot, I really like the way panels in airliner cockpits appear
to be very modular. They look like they are mounted by screws on rails, sort of
like rack mounted equipment. I thought, this would be a neat way to design my
cyberdeck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s what I started with:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/image_6487327.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I 3D printed some rails, like 19” rack rails. I started with round holes, but
then after more thinking, I decided to make the holes hexagons. This would
allow me to insert brass hexagon nuts anywhere I wanted a screw. I chose M3
sized hex nuts, and ordered an assortment case of M3 screws from Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the parts seen in that photo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tinkercad.com/things/lstazDYnaeh&quot;&gt;3D printed rails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08N5XDHMW/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o04_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;M3 screw assortment pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00NQ87PVK/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o04_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Hexagon brass
nuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01M3UQX1Y/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o08_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;Z88 LED
keyboard&lt;/a&gt;
I love this keyboard, it’s loud and clicky, reminds me of my dad’s Kaypro 10
in 1985&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07H8F5HYJ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o03_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&quot;&gt;12V 38400MAH Lithium Ion battery
pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi 4&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi 7” touch screen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harbor Freight equipment case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come in Part 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 14:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//cyberdeck-part-1</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-1"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/cyberdeck-part-1</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tracking high altitude balloons with WSPR</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been fascinated with amateur high altitude balloons.  I’ve always
wanted to launch a balloon with a radio payload and see where it goes and what
data it collects. But, never have I ever, launched a balloon or helped out with
a launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I checked on the current state of the art, and I was blown away!
Amateur radio operators are flying solar powered WSPR transmitters on balloons
that stay aloft for weeks at a time. They circumnavigate the globe multiple
times. Several are out there now floating around the earth at about 12000m (40000ft)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was already operating a WSPR station from time to time, I’m fascinated that
I can put 1 watt into a piece of wire in my attic, and see stations all over the
world hear my signal.  More on WSPR here at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsprnet.org/drupal/&quot;&gt;WSPRNet&lt;/a&gt;.
So naturally, the challenge of picking up one of these
balloons was too much to pass up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WSPR balloons are transmitting a standard WSPR packet, which contains a 4 digit
maidenhead grid location. This defines about a 11000 sq km (7000 sq mi) box
where the balloon is located. But some balloons are transmitting a second WSPR
packet that’s non-standard. It encodes an additonal 2 digits for the grid
square, plus temperature and altitude in a single WSPR packet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a tracking site called &lt;a href=&quot;https://tracker.habhub.org/&quot;&gt;habhub&lt;/a&gt; that’s a neat site where you can see these
WSPR balloons, plus APRS and LORA balloons as well. But I was a bit
disappointed in the frequency of updates on the WSPR balloons. I wanted to try
querying the WSPR spots data and decode the packets myself. I found that Dave,
SM3ULC, has written a python script doing this and put it up on Github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sm3ulc/hab-wspr&quot;&gt;sm3ulc/hab-wspr&lt;/a&gt;.
I cloned it and tinkered around with it, and decided to write a Ruby version
based on his ideas. Thanks to him, the math formulas were already worked out
for extracting the telemetry from the WSPR packets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My version is up on Github and there’s more details there if you find this
interesting:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jeremyfsu/hab-wspr-telemetry-decoder&quot;&gt;jeremyfsu/hab-wspr-telemetry-decoder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, my Ruby script runs every few minutes, queries for WSPR spots that
are balloons, decodes them, then formats APRS packets from the data.  I don’t
send the APRS packets into the APRS network, there are people who do this
already for
the balloons. I don’t see the need to feed the already engorged APRS network.  Instead, I’m sending the APRS packets to a local
&lt;a href=&quot;http://he.fi/aprsc/&quot;&gt;APRSC&lt;/a&gt;
server, then mapping them with &lt;a href=&quot;http://xastir.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;Xastir&lt;/a&gt;.
Xastir is taking screenshots every few minutes and dropping them here:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://home.jeremywalworth.com/aprs&quot;&gt;home.jeremywalworth.com/aprs&lt;/a&gt; 
“That maps looks like it’s from 2003!” you say. Yes, I run Xastir with a basic setup. 
But yes, I would like to make an embedded Google Map on a page and plot the positions. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://tracker.habhub.org/&quot;&gt;Habhub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://aprs.fi&quot;&gt;aprs.fi&lt;/a&gt; already do
an outstanding job at this. However, I think it would be cool to see my data
plotted on my own embedded Google Map without sending to the APRS network or
Habhub.  Stay tuned, maybe I’ll get around to
doing this. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s my hope that a future balloon operator might find my Ruby script useful
for transmitting their balloon packets into the APRS network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 12:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://skyfarer.cloud//tracking-high-altitude-balloons</link>
        <link href="https://skyfarer.cloud/tracking-high-altitude-balloons"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://skyfarer.cloud/tracking-high-altitude-balloons</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
